BRIAN WALKER

23301 Kipling Street #212, Oak Park, MI 48237 • Cell: (248) 636-7086 • brianwalker150@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Experienced logistics and transportation professional offering exceptional analytical, problem-solving and interpersonal skills. Seeks a position offering opportunities for growth in a fast-paced, engaging environment.

Skills

- Warehouse and manufacturing operations
- Proficient in computers and related software applications including MS Office
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- Excellent time management
- Skilled multi-tasker
- Proactive

Work History

Logistics Coordinator, 08/2016 to Current

APL Logistics - Farmington Hills, MI

- E-mailed suppliers, carriers and customers with shipping updates.
- Arranged expedites, and assigned shipments to carriers in a centralized database.
- Took corrective action in the case of accidents and delays to minimize extra expenses.
- Performed audits on numerous shipments to ensure accurate delivery times.

Data Clerk. 01/2016 to 08/2016

Ryder Logistics - Novi, MI

- Gathered, logged and monitored various shipping data.
- Communicated with dispatchers, warehouses and customers regarding outgoing orders.
- Updated the database with changes in carrier status.
- Effectively managed a high-volume of inbound and outbound customer calls.

Logistics & Transportation Clerk, 09/2014 to 12/2015

Ryder Logistics (General Motors Orion Assembly) - Orion Charter Township, MI

- Updated dock schedule and informed appropriate personnel of any scheduling changes including cancellations and expedites.
- Directed truck drivers and assigned dock doors for various inbound/outbound shipments.
- Worked closely with plant management to resolve shipping errors and delays.
- Used system mainframe (GM MGO) to input shipping information and verify inventory.

Security Officer, 02/2009 to 09/2014

Shepherd Security Faygo Beverages - Detroit, MI

- Monitored and authorized entrance and departure of employees, visitors, and other persons to guard against theft and maintain security of premises.
- Wrote reports of daily activities and irregularities including equipment or property damage, theft, presence of unauthorized persons, and unusual occurrences.

Inventory Associate, 11/2007 to 02/2009

WIS International - Farmington Hills, MI

- Took inventory and examined merchandise at various retailers, while working at a rapid pace.
- Verified inventory computations by comparing them to physical counts of stock, and investigated discrepancies.

File Clerk. 05/2007 to 09/2007

50th District Court - Pontiac, MI

- Organized folders and paperwork, filed reference materials, and used computers to enter and retrieve data.
- Retrieved information from files in response to requests from authorized users.

Education

Bachelor of Arts: Media Arts and Studies, 2013

Wayne State University - Detroit, MI

• Coursework in Business/Media Law, Computer Applications and Communications